Girls in my magazines are a lot nakeder.
我看的杂志中的女孩多数都是裸体的
Oh, hey, Joey.
嘿, 乔伊
-Hey. -Listen, I need to ask you something.
-嘿 -我有点事要跟你商量
You know how my stepdad's in prison?
你还记得我继父在监狱里的事吧?
-Yeah. -Yeah.
-嗯 -嗯
He was supposed to get a weekend furlough so he could go to the wedding.
恩, 这个周末他本来有个假期的  这样明天他就能来参加我的婚礼了
But he just called and..
但是他刚刚打电话来说...
Well, apparently stabbing lceman in the exercise yard couldn't wait till Monday.
嗯, 他在操场上捅了一个送冰的家伙  他就不能忍到礼拜一吗！
-So he can't come? -No.
-这么说他来不了了吗? -对
And so there's no one to walk me down the aisle. And..
这么一来就没人挽着我走过红地毯了  所以, 嗯...
Well, I would just really love it if you would do it.
嗯, 我很希望你能挽着我
-Seriously? -Yeah.
-真的? -对
You've, you know, sort of been like a dad to me.
你知道, 一直以来我都把你当作父亲一样
You've always, you know, looked out for me and shared your wisdom.
我是说, 你一直以来都很照顾我, 和我一起分享你的智慧
I am pretty "wisdomous."
我的确很有智慧
So, what do you say?
所以...你觉得呢?
Are you kidding? Phoebe, I would be honored.
当然, 这是我的荣幸, 菲比
Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢啦
I hope..
我希望
I hope you know how much you mean to me.
你能够了解你对我来说有多么重要
Listen, I hope..
听着, 我希望
I hope that you know..
我希望你知道......
I don't want you to see your father cry. Go to your room!
我不想让你看到爸爸哭的样子 回自己的房间去!
The One With Phoebe's Wedding
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
Oh, no, no, no. Let your dad get this.
哦, 不不不, 让你爸付吧
It's my wedding planner. She's driving me crazy!
哦, 是我的婚礼策划人 她快把我逼疯了
Hello? Okay, stop screaming!
喂, 嘿, 行了行了, 别这么大声嚷嚷!
Okay, so halibut.
好, 那就比目鱼好了
All right, so salmon. Either way. I don't..
好吧, 三文鱼也行, 随便什么都好
-It doesn't matter to me. -Well, it matters to me!
-我无所谓  -可我有所谓!
Well, I don't care. So you pick.
好吧, 我不在乎, 听你的好了
Did you just hang up on me?
你刚才挂我的电话来着?
All right, look, I need you at the rehearsal dinner tonight at 1800 hours.
好了, 听着, 我要你在晚上十八点整 准时到达婚礼彩排的现场
Okay. What time is that?
哦, 好, 那是几点钟啊?
You don't know military time?
你不知道军用时刻吗?
I must have been in missile training the day they taught that.
哦, 当时我在接受导弹训练, 所以没学到
Just subtract 12.
减12就行了
Okay, so 1800 minus 12..
噢, 那1800减去12
is 1788.
就是1788
-Six o'clock! -Okay.
-6点钟! -噢
Hold on. Yeah? Geller here.
哦, 等一下 好, 我是盖勒
No, I said it has to be there by 4:00. Goodbye.
不, 我说过了, 一定要在4点之前送到  再见
How hard is it to make an ice sculpture?
天哪 做一个冰雕有那么难么?
Harder than it looks.
比看起来难！
Wait. Ice sculpture? That sounds really fancy.
冰雕? 太隆重了吧
I told you, I just want a simple wedding.
我跟你说过我只想要一个简单的婚礼就好
Please, honey, leave the details to me.
放心好了, 亲爱的 一切都包在我身上
Now, I wanna make this day as special for you as I can.
为了你, 我会尽量把这一天弄得特别一些
I was thinking the harpist should wear white.
好了, 我打算让港湾乐队(the Harbours) 穿成白色
Harpist? My friend Marjorie is playing the steel drums.
港湾乐队? 不是我朋友马崔来敲钢鼓的吗?
-Oh, she backed out. -She did? Why?
-哦, 她退出了  -她退出了? 为什么?
I made her.
我叫她这么做的
Steel drums don't really say "elegant wedding."
钢鼓和高雅的婚礼不太搭调
-Nor does Marjorie's overwhelming scent. -Hey!
-而且马崔的体味太浓了 -嘿!
She will shower when Tibet is free.
西藏独立之后她会洗澡的
-Hey. You look great. -You too.
-嘿 你看起来真美 -你也是
I'm glad we're having a rehearsal dinner. I rarely practice my meals before I eat.
我真高兴能有这么一次彩排, 我打算 在把这些食物吃下去之前, 好好跟它们演习一下
What did we say was your one gift to us?
嘿, 还记得你答应过 要送给我们的礼物是什么吗？
No stupid jokes, but I thought that was for the actual wedding.
不开无聊的玩笑, 我以为那只是在正式的婚礼上
Rehearse it.
先演习一下吧
Hi.
嗨
-Thanks for coming, you guys. -Oh, yeah..
-真高兴你们都来了  -哦, 我...
I was.. I was going for a handshake.
我只打算握个手
That why your hand's against my crotch?
所以你把手顶在我的裤裆上?
-That is why. -Yeah.
-没错  -好了
So, Rach, where's Emma?
瑞秋, 艾玛呢？
Monica made me send her to my mom's.
哦, 莫妮卡让我把她送到我妈那里去了
Apparently, babies and weddings don't mix.
显然, 婴儿和婚礼可掺合不到一块儿
Are you still crying about your damn baby?
你还在为你那烦人的小家伙哭哭啼啼的?
Phoebe, you got to keep the line moving. Remember,20 seconds per person.
菲比, 待会儿（在致酒时）你要说快点  记住, 跟每个人都是20秒
You see these clowns all the time.
你和这些家伙天天见面
You must give me the name of your wedding planner.
你最好把婚礼策划人的名字给我
I wanna throw a really tense party.
我真想把紧张的舞会抛开
-Hey, you're Mike's parents, right? -Yes, we are.
-嘿, 你们是麦克的父母吧? -是的
Our little ones are growing up fast, aren't they?
眼看着我们的小家伙们都长这么大了, 是吧？
-How's that? -You know..
-你说什么? -你知道
on one hand, you're happy for them. On the other, it's hard to let go.
我们做父母的, 一方面替他们感到高兴 但另一方面, 心里又难免有点舍不得
How do you want to divide up the holidays?
你怎么能想着把假日给分开呢?
I was thinking Thanksgiving at my place, Christmas at yours.
我在想感恩节在我家, 圣诞在你家
Who in God's name are you?
你到底是谁啊?
I'm not that fond of you either, buddy. I'm just trying to be nice for the kids.
嘿, 我也不喜欢你们, 知道吗? 我是看在孩子们的面子上才跟你们客气的
You know what? We have no idea what we're doing in the wedding tomorrow.
你知道我刚想起什么吗? 咱俩还没有被分配在婚礼上的任务呢
I thought we'd be groomsmen. They would have asked us by now.
对啊,我觉得咱们会是伴郎 但都到这会儿了, 他们怎么还不跟咱俩说呢?
When did they ask you to be a bridesmaid?
你什么时候知道你是伴娘的?
-November. -I wanna say it's not looking good.
-呃... 11月? -我觉得情况有点不妙
-Hey, Phoebe? -Sorry?
-嘿, 菲比！ -干吗?
You haven't told these guys what they're doing in the wedding yet.
呃, 你还没有告诉他们俩在婚礼上要做什么呢
Well, they're not in the wedding.
哦, 那个, 他们不会出现在婚礼仪式上
What?
什么?
Well..
呃
this is really awkward.
气氛有点尴尬
Oh, and I can leave.
哦, 这儿没我的事儿了
I'm sorry, you guys. But Mike's got his brother and his friends from school.
真对不起你们, 但麦克有一个哥哥 而且还有他在学校的死党
So, you know, you were..
所以...
If it helps, you were next in line. You just missed the cut.
如果这么说能让你们好受一点, 你们两个是头号候补, 就差那么一点
Oh, man.
哦, 天哪.
This is like figure skating team all over again.
以前在选花样滑冰队员的时候就是这样
I mean, synchronized swimming.
我是说, 水上芭蕾
I mean.. I mean, the balance beam.
我的意思是, 平衡木
-Help me. -Football.
-帮帮忙. -橄榄球!
Thank you.
谢了
Oh, Phoebe, spit that out. That has pork in it.
噢, 菲比, 赶快吐出来 那里面有猪肉
I thought the pot stickers were supposed to be vegetarian?
我记得那个砂锅应该是全素的？
Yeah, I changed them. I sent you a fax about it.
啊, 是的, 但我做了点变动 我发传真告诉你了
I don't have a fax machine.
可是我根本没有传真机啊
Well, then there are gonna be a few surprises.
哈! 那你可能会发现有一些意外
I can't believe we're gonna be the only people not in the wedding.
我简直不敢相信 只有我们俩个不会出现在仪式上
-I know. I hate being left out of things. -And it's a wedding.
-是啊, 我讨厌被冷落  -要知道这是一个婚礼!
It'll be weird if I'm not in it.
如果缺了我感觉会很奇怪的
-Hey, guys, how's it going? -Fine.
-嘿, 你们俩怎么样? -还好啦
We're sitting here, alone, doing nothing. It's our rehearsal for tomorrow.
这不, 我们正坐着呢, 就我们俩, 无所事事  我们在为明天做彩排呢
Look, about tomorrow, I've got a question for you.
嘿, 关于明天, 我有个问题问你们
I found out one of my groomsmen had an emergency and can't make it.
我刚知道我的一个伴郎出了点急事, 所以不能来了
-What happened? -Who cares? And..?
-出什么事了? -管那么多干嘛! 所以...?
And I was wondering if one of you guys..
所以我在想, 也许你们两个人中的一个能...
-I'll do it! -Me!
-我来替他! -不, 不 我, 我!
You both wanna do it? There's only room for one.
你们两个都想做? 呃, 只有一个名额
Pick me. I look great in a tux, and I won't steal focus.
选我! 我适合穿燕尾服 而且我这模样也不会抢你的镜头
No, Mike. No, no, you wanna pick me. I mean.. Watch.
不, 麦克, 不 选我! 我的意思是, 瞧!
You know, I really don't feel very comfortable making this decision.
呃, 我不太习惯来做这种决定
You know, Phoebe knows you better. I'm gonna let her choose.
菲比更了解你们 我会让她来选
Well, if Phoebe's choosing, then say hello to Mike's next groomsman.
嗯, 如果是菲比来选的话, 你现在就可以跟麦克的新伴郎打招呼了
Oh, I will. But I will need a mirror..
哦, 我会的 但我要先找一面镜子
as he is me.
因为这个人就是我
-Please. You're going down. -You are going "downer."
-省省吧, 你逊死了  -你更逊.
They say that on the figure skating team?
他们在选花样滑冰队员的时候 就是这么说你的？
I wouldn't know. I didn't make it.
我不知道, 我没被选上
You know I'm filling in for Phoebe's stepdad tomorrow, right?
明天我会扮演菲比的继父, 你知道吧?
-Yeah. Yeah. Hey, thanks for doing that. -Oh, hey, my pleasure.
-知道 很感谢你能这么做  -哦, 嘿, 这是我的荣幸
So, what are your intentions with my Phoebe?
那好, 你对我的菲比有什么企图?
-I intend to marry her. -Oh, a wiseacre.
-我“企图”跟她结婚  -哦, 你这一拳打得还挺聪明
I understand you plan to support your wife by playing the piano?
照我的理解, 你似乎打算靠弹钢琴来养活老婆
Isn't that kind of unstable?
这种工作好像不太稳定
-No more so than acting. -Strike two.
-哦, 跟演戏比起来还算好啦  -第二拳
You're right. She probably will support me.
你说得对 我可能需要她来养活
Hey, unless we move in with you, Dad.
嘿, 除非我们搬去跟你一起住, 爸爸
Strike three.
第三拳
You only get one more, Mike.
你只有最后一次机会了, 麦克
-Michael, can I see you for a moment? -Yeah, sure.
-麦克, 我能和你聊聊吗? -当然可以
This was..
那真是..
weird.
太怪了
-Hi. -Hey.
-嗨 -嘿
What's with the face?
脸怎么了?
That Mike has got no respect. I'm not sure about him.
那个麦克不尊重人. 我不知道他人怎么样
Wait, that's not him. There he is.
等下, 那个不是他, 他人在这呢
So? What did you decide?
怎么样? 你决定了没有?
I decided to pee.
我决定...要去厕所
You have to choose one of us to be in your wedding.
你要在我们两个人里选一个来参加仪式
-One of the groomsmen fell out. -Oh, no, no.
-有个伴郎来不了了 -哦, 不
I can't choose between you two. I love you both so much.
你们两个叫我怎么选啊  你们对我来说同样重要
Just not enough to put us in the original wedding party.
的确重要, 差一点就能参加原定的婚礼了
Such bitterness.
真痛苦
Best to keep that attitude in the seats.
最好把这态度留到婚礼
Come on, Phoebe. We both really want to do this, and it's up to you.
来吧, 菲比. 我们都想参加, 而且由你来决定
But I don't wanna choose. It's..
我没法选 这太...
Okay, wait. Rach?
哦, 等一下 瑞秋！
Listen, I have a very special bridesmaid task for you to do.
呃, 我需要你作为伴娘替我选样东西
Goody! What is it?
太棒了! 选什么?
Well, there's a spot open for only one groomsman..
嗯, 现在伴郎有一个空缺
and you have to choose between Ross and Chandler. So good luck with that.
你需要在罗斯和钱德中间选一个 所以...祝你好运
What? What, what, what? No, I don't wanna do that.
什么, 什么? 不, 不要, 我不想选这个
I guess I have to find a new bridesmaid.
好吧, 我想我只好去另找一个新的伴娘了
I'll do it!
我来!
Okay, it's 2100 hours.
好, 现在是21:00
-Time for your toast. -Do I have time to go to the bathroom?
-到你敬酒的时间了  -我能不能先去一下洗手间?
You had a bathroom break at 2030. Pee on your own time, Mike.
你去洗手间的时间是20:30  要专时专用, 麦克.
In regards to the toasts, okay, you wanna keep them short.
关于致酒词, 要尽量简短一些
Nothing kills a rehearsal dinner like long speeches. Okay.
婚礼彩排的时候 没有什么比又臭又长的致酒词更烦人了
You just get in, do your thing, and get out.
你要做的就是：上场, 干活, 然后走人
Is that what you say to Chandler?
你跟钱德也这么说?
It's 2101, and I am not amused.
现在已经21:01了, 而且我一点也不觉得好笑
Okay.
好吧
The bride and groom have a few words they'd like to say.
新郎和新娘要说“两”句
Okay. Hello, everyone.
嗨, 大家好
And thank you all for being here tonight. So tomorrow's the big event.
很高兴各位今晚能够光临  明天就是正式的婚礼了
Some of you might not know, but Mike and I didn't get off to the best start.
大家可能还不知道, 我和麦克的开始一点也不精彩
Yeah. My friend Joey and I..
呃, 是这样的
decided to fix each other up with friends. So I..
当时乔伊和我决定相互替对方介绍朋友
Oh, okay. I..
所以呢, 我, 我...
I thought about it, and I fixed him up with my friend Mary Ellen..
我... 我当时仔细考虑了半天, 然后决定把我的朋友马莉兰介绍给他
who couldn't be here tonight, because.. It's not..
马莉兰今晚没有来, 因为她...
It's not important. Well, she's in rehab.
这不重要, 她...
Anyway. So Joey said that he was fixing me up with his friend Mike..
总之, 乔伊说他要介绍他的朋友麦克给我认识
only he didn't have a friend Mike, so he just brought my Mike.
但他并不认识什么叫麦克的朋友 所以他就把我的麦克, 呃, 带去了
And.. And..
然后...
But despite, you know.. It got good.
尽管如此... 呃, 结果呢, 结果还不错
I wanna take a moment to mention my mother, who couldn't be here.
好, 我想要在这里用一点点时间 来缅怀一下我的母亲  她今晚不能出席,因为...
Oh, God.
哦, 天哪
And.. And moment's over.
呃, 缅怀时间结束
So okay.. Oh, no, forget that.
好了, 呃... 哦, 这个就不说了, 然后...
I can forget that. Oh, this is funny.
我可以跳过这里哦, 这个很有意思
Oh, but you need to know that to get that.
哦 但首先你得知道...
So.. Oh, well, okay.
哦, 好吧, 我...
I.. Okay.
我...
Okay, Monica, I can't do it like this!
好了, 莫妮卡, 我再也受不了了!
This is my wedding, okay? I don't want this..
这是我的婚礼! 知道吗？我不需要这样
Or this.. Or this..
或者这样, 或者这样,...
Okay? I just wanted a simple wedding..
好吗？ 我要的只是一个简单的婚礼
where my fiance can go to the bathroom any time he wants!
我要我的未婚夫能够随心所欲地上厕所!
-You know what? You're done. -What?
-你知道吗, 你玩完了  -什么?
You're fired!
你被炒了!
Cheers.
干杯!
-Hey. -Happy wedding day.
-嘿! -新婚快乐!
Happy my wedding day to you.
哦, 也祝你快乐
Joey, listen, this is gonna be bridesmaid central, all right?
好了, 乔伊, 听着, 从现在开始 这里是伴娘的地盘, 明白了吗?
We're gonna have hair and makeup in the bathroom.
我们要在卫生间里面做头发, 然后...
I had to move a couple things in the fridge to make room for the corsages.
哦, 我要把冰箱里的东西挪一下 给襟花腾出地方
Man! I wouldn't have had breakfast if I knew there was gonna be corsages.
噢, 真是的! 早知道有襟花我就不吃早饭了
Hi.
呃
About last night..
关于昨晚...
I know you're under a lot of stress, and..
我知道你压力很大, 所以...
Well, even though the things you said were a little hurtful to me..
尽管你说的话让我有点伤心
as someone who's never been fired before..
作为一个从未被解雇的人..
What about in high school..
高中时是什么感觉..
when that yogurt store let you go for sampling toppings?
当卖乳酸的小店让你做样品招牌?
Everyone there did that.
大伙都这么做
Yeah, but did everybody owe 3 grand at the end of the summer?
对啊! 但是不是每个人 都在暑假结束时赚了3000块?
My point is..
我的意思是...
Well, I'm willing to take my job back.
好吧, 我愿意复职
Oh, well, that's okay.
哦, 还是算了吧
I think you and I will do much better if you're just here as a bridesmaid.
我觉得如果你只做伴娘的话情况会好得多
Is that so?
哦, 既然你这么说
Okay.
好吧
If that's really what you want, then here.
如果你真这么想的话, 好吧 给你这个耳机
I give you the headset. I don't really wanna give you the headset.
我还是不太想给你这个耳机
I guess if you're taking over, then you should probably return these messages.
还有就是, 如果你要接手的话 你大概需要回复这些信息
This is a lot.
哇, 真不少啊
But I'm sure you can handle this. I have won awards..
我相信你能处理它们  我是说, 尽管...
for my organizational skills. But I'm sure you'll do fine.
我曾经获得过组织技能的证书, 但是呢 我相信你肯定没问题
-You've won awards? -I printed them out on my computer.
-你获得过证书? -是我用自己的电脑打印出来的.
-Hey. -Hi.
-嘿  -嗨
-Where's Rach? -She's in her room. Why?
-瑞秋呢？ -她在自己的房间, 有事吗?
I have to talk to her about this groomsman situation.
我要跟她谈谈关于那个伴郎的问题
I'm not gonna watch Chandler up there while I'm in the seats like some chump.
我可不想像个傻子一样坐在那儿 看着钱德在婚礼上露脸
This wedding isn't about you.
这可不是你的婚礼
It's not? Then who's it about?
不是吗? 那是谁的啊?
Well, it used to be about me, but now I have no idea.
好吧, 这婚礼曾经和我有关 但现在我也不知道了
My God, you're breathtaking.
啊, 天哪, 你简直美得令人窒息
What do you want?
你想干嘛?
You haven't by any chance chosen a groomsman yet, have you?
你还没决定伴郎的人选吧?
Ross, please don't make this harder than it already is.
哦, 罗斯, 求你了 我已经很为难了, 你就别再添乱了
I'm not. I'm making it easier. Pick me.
我没有啊  我是在让事情简单化, 选我!
Chandler said it's important to him too.
可是, 钱德也说这个机会对他十分重要
I'm sorry, did you and Chandler go out?
抱歉, 你要和钱德出去吗?
Do you and Chandler have a huge history, huh?
你和钱德曾经抱过吗?
Do you and Chandler have a child together?
你和钱德有孩子吗?
If I said yes that would freak you out, wouldn't it?
如果我说是, 就会让你发疯, 是不是?
Listen. Listen.
听着听着
Whoever you pick is gonna walk down the aisle with you.
无论你选谁, 你要知道 你选的这个人将要跟你一起走过红地毯
Now, I promise I won't say a word. But if you pick Chandler..
我可以保证, 到时候我一个字也不会说 但如果你选钱德的话
he's gonna be whispering stupid jokes in your ear the whole time.
他肯定会一直在你耳朵旁边 嘀咕他那些无聊的玩笑
Oh, you are the lesser of two evils.
哦.....你确实强一点..
Yes!
没错
Don't say anything to Chandler until I talk to him.
先别跟钱德说, 我来和他说
-You got it. -Okay.
-明白了 -好
I cannot believe you played the Emma card.
真不相信你玩艾玛的卡片
Oh, please. I was prepared to offer you my body.
行了! 我要把自己献给你了
Oh, my God! And I didn't hold out.
喔 天啊! 我竟然没阻止你
You know, normally, that would hurt my feelings..
你知道, 那通常都会伤我的感情..
but today, I'm a groomsman.
但是今天, 我是男傧相
Sven, I don't understand what you're saying. What is wrong with the flowers?
塞文, 我不知道你在说什么  花又有什么问题了?
"Lorkins"? What the hell are "lorkins"?
Lorgans? Lorgans是什么见鬼的玩意?
I know.
我知道
-Hey. -Mike, if you were Swedish..
-嘿. -嘿, 麦克, 如果你是瑞典人
and you were saying the word "lorkins, " what flower would that be?
你用lorgans来代表一种花, 会是什么花呢?
-Orchids? -Right there!
-兰花(Orchids)? -真棒
That's why I'm marrying you.
我就是因为这个才嫁给你的
Hello, Michael.
你好, 麦克.
Joseph.
乔瑟夫.
May I have a word with you, please?
我能跟你说两句吗?
You wanna step it up there?
你想去那里说吗?
This is..
这里真是...
great.
棒极了
Have a seat.
坐
Last night..
昨天晚上,...
I tried to welcome you into my family.
我试着欢迎你进入我们的家族
And instead, you disrespect me.
然而, 你对我很不尊重
I cannot allow this.
我不能容忍这一点
Are you rehearsing for some really bad Mafia movie?
你是在排练什么劣制黑社会电影吗?
More back talk.
还敢顶嘴
And yes, I may be borrowing a few lines from my recent unsuccessful audition..
没错, 最近我是参加了一次《荣誉家族》续集的试镜
for Family Honor 2: This A-Time It's A-Personal.
我从剧本中挑了两句
Joey, I kind of have a lot to do today. What do you want?
乔伊, 我今天比较忙 你到底想要干嘛?
I want you to take this seriously!
我想要你认真一点
Phoebe is very, very important to me, okay?
菲比对我来说非常非常的重要, 知道吗？
I wanna make sure you are gonna take care of her.
我要你保证, 你会好好照顾她
Joe, I love Phoebe.
乔伊, 我爱菲比
She's the most important thing in my life.
在我的生命中没有什么比她更重要
I'd die before I let anything happen to her.
我宁死也不会让她受到任何伤害
That's what I wanted to hear.
这才是我想听的
Because she's family, okay?
因为我当她是家人, 知道吗？
And now you're gonna be family.
现在你也要成为家里的一份子了
And there's nothing more important in the whole world than family.
在世界上没有什么事比家庭更重要
That must have been one lousy movie.
那个电影可真是烂得可以
That was me!
不是台词, 是我说的!
-Hi. -Let's talk about this groomsman thing.
-嘿 -嘿, 我能跟你商量一下伴郎的事吗？
If you pick Ross, he'll walk you down the aisle just fine.
如果你选罗斯, 你知道的 你们俩只能安安静静地走过红地毯
But if you choose me..
但如果你选我的话
you'll be getting some comedy.
你可就有乐子听了
Even so..
即便如此
I think I'm gonna pick Ross.
我想我还是选罗斯
Yeah, I figured you might..
没错, 我觉得你可能..
because of the history, and you used to love him..
因为过去, 而且你曾经爱过他..
and you guys have a baby.
而且还生了个孩子
Well, thank you for respecting my decision.
那么就谢谢你尊重我的决定了
Let me tell you why you need to pick me.
我来告诉你为什么你要选我
See, when I was a kid, you know, I was always left out of everything..
当我还是个孩子的时候, 无论做什么 我总是被冷落的一个
and it really made me feel insecure.
你要知道, 这种经历总是让我缺乏安全感
I was always picked last in gym..
在运动场上我永远都是被人家挑剩下的那个
even behind that fat exchange student who didn't know the rules to baseball.
就算是那个交换学生, 那个连什么是棒球 也不知道的傻大个儿也排在我前面
I mean, this guy would strike out and then run to third.
那个家伙一打着球, 撂下球棒就朝三垒上跑
It's just so humiliating.
真是太耻辱了
I mean, you know how it feels to be left out of things, right?
我是说, 你应该知道被排在万事之外的感觉, 对吧?
-No. -No.
-不 -不
Anyway, if I'm the only one left out of this wedding..
总之, 如果我成为唯一一个不能参加婚礼的人
I just know that all those feelings are gonna come rushing back.
以前那些凄惨的回忆就会再次浮现在眼前
All right, fine, I pick you.
好吧, 我选你
Yes!
太棒了！
Make "groom" for Chandler.
终于有钱德的一席之地了  (Make groom for钱德, groom和room谐音)
Oh, my.
噢, 我的天哪!
No, we're gonna do it my way. Because your way is stupid.
不, 要照我说的做  因为你的办法太笨了
All right, I got to go. I have another call, Reverend.
好了, 有电话正打进来, 我要挂了, 牧师
Hello?
喂?
-I'm glad we had this little talk. -Yes.
-这次小小的谈话还算愉快  -是啊, 没错
And thanks for all the wedding night advice.
对了, 谢谢你关于洞房的那些建议
That didn't make me uncomfortable at all.
我一点都不觉得尴尬
All right, so I'll see everybody tonight.
好了, 就这样吧 大家晚上见喽
-Okay. -Bye.
-好 -再见
Did you guys know that there's a giant ice sculpture in the hall?
呃, 你们知道在走廊里有个大号的冰雕么？
Oh, my God, what's it doing here?
哦 天哪, 为什么会在这儿的？
I guess it got sent to the billing address as opposed to the shipping address.
呃, 我猜是送货的家伙 把投递地址和付款人地址搞混了
-What a pickle. -Oh, my God, everything's such a mess.
-哦, 真是个蠢货! -我的天哪! 什么事都是一团糟
Why is this happening to me?
为什么这些事情会发生在我身上？
How bad do you wanna stick your tongue on that?
你们想不想用舌头去舔舔它?
-How's it going? -Good.
-你怎么样? -我很好啊
I'm just getting some coffee so I'm alert for the wedding.
我来要点咖啡喝 这样我能在婚礼上清醒一点
That's what I was doing too.
我也是这么打算的
Well, you have fun tonight.
那好, 今晚玩得高兴点
-You too. -Oh, I will.
-你也是  -哦, 我会的
Me too.
我也会的
Wait a minute. I know why I'm being such an ass. Why are you?
慢着, 我知道自己为什么这么得意 但你为什么也这样？
-I'm not supposed to tell you. -I'm not supposed to tell you.
-我不能告诉你  -我不能告诉你
Did Rachel say you could be in the wedding?
瑞秋说过你可以参加婚礼了吗?
-Yes. -She told me that too!
-没错 -她也那么告诉我的
I don't believe this. I played the Emma card.
真不能相信, 我玩了艾玛的卡片
I looked into my soul.
我审视了自己的灵魂
You told us both we could be in the wedding?
你同时答应我们两个人参加仪式？
In my defense, you weren't supposed to tell each other!
我的解释是, 你们不应该告诉对方的!
Rachel, only one of us can do it. You have to choose.
瑞秋, 只有一个人可以参加婚礼仪式  你必须要选一个
You and me together again.
你和我, 我们又能在一起了
Rach, Rach? Knock-knock.
瑞秋, 瑞秋, 咚, 咚（敲门声）
-Who's there? -I'll tell you at the wedding.
-是谁啊? -在婚礼上我再告诉你
Hey, I forgot my scarf.
嘿, 我忘戴围巾了
I can't do this. I don't know which one of you guys to pick.
我做不来, 我真的不知道应该选谁
Oh, you haven't picked yet? Oh, good, because I had an idea.
哦, 你还没选好呢 我倒是有个好主意
I thought it would be fun if the third groomsman was my family dog, Chappy.
我觉得如果由我们家的狗恰皮 来担任伴郎的话 肯定很有意思
What? A dog? No. Rachel gets to choose.
什么, 一只狗? 不, 让瑞秋来选
Wow, this is a tough one.
真是难以抉择啊
I think I'm gonna have to go with the dog.
看起来我只有选那只狗了
So, what you're saying is that the chef is at the Hamilton Club..
等一下, 你是说, 厨子已经到Hamilton俱乐部了
but the food is not? And the drinks are there but the bartender is not?
但食物还没有送到？ 饮料和酒水已经送到了, 但男招待还没有到？
Are you freaking kidding me?
你... 他妈的开什么玩笑!?
How's it going?
怎么样了?
-Help me. -What?
-帮帮我... -什么?
I want you to be crazy bitch again.
我想让你做回疯婆子
Really?
真的?
Please?
求你了
-You really want me to come back? -More than I wanna get married.
-你真想让我回来? -嗯, 胜过我想结婚
Okay, people, we are back in business!
好, 伙计们, 我们回来了
Oh, God, I have missed you so much. Okay.
哦 天哪, 我可想死你了
Get your hair and makeup done. I'll take care of everything.
好了, 去做你的头发吧  这儿一切交给我好了
-Hey, what are you guys gonna do? -About what?
-嘿, 你们打算怎么办? -什么怎么办?
The blizzard. I just saw on the news..
暴风雪啊 我刚看电视
it's the worst snowstorm in 20 years.
说这是20年来最大的一场暴风雪
They already closed all the bridges and tunnels.
所有的桥和隧道都关闭了
But the band and the photographer are coming in from New Jersey.
可是乐队和摄像师还要从新泽西赶过来呢！
I don't think they are.
看来他们够呛
Looks like you're not gonna be in the wedding, either.
哈哈, 看起来你恐怕也参加不了仪式了吧
So sorry, Phoebe.
真遗憾啊, 菲比
-Well, the club lost its power. -The news said most of the city did.
-俱乐部停电了  -是啊,听新闻说,市里大部分地区都停电了
-Since when do you watch the news? -For your information..
-你从什么时候开始看起新闻来了? -呃,告诉你好了
since they hired a very hot weather girl.
从那个靓女开始主持天气预报的时候
I can't believe you aren't getting married today.
真不敢相信, 你们两个今天的婚礼办不成了
I know.
是啊
It's so beautiful out there. You always wanted to get married outside.
哇, 你们看哪,外面真的好美  你不是总想在户外举行婚礼吗？
-Why don't you just do it on the street? -What?
-你们俩干嘛不干脆在街上结婚呢？ -什么?
Well, look, it's hardly snowing anymore.
看哪, 雪几乎已经停了
I mean, you couldn't ask for a more romantic setting.
我想, 没有比这更加浪漫的布景了
This could be the simple wedding you've always wanted.
这不正是你一直想要的简单的婚礼吗？
What do you think?
你认为呢?
I think I wanna get married to you today.
我只想今天就跟你结婚
Me too. Monica, do you think we could do it?
我也是 莫妮卡, 你觉得这样可行吗?
Affirmative!
赞成
Okay, let's get these chairs out here!
好！ 大家把椅子都搬出来
Gunther, hit the Christmas lights.
甘瑟, 把圣诞用的灯饰都打亮
Okay, who left the ice sculpture on the steam grate?
喂！ 是哪个家伙把冰雕放在热水井旁边的?
-Michael. -Hey, you made it. Great. Chappy!
-麦克 -嘿, 你成功了, 太棒了. 恰皮!
-There you go. -Hi. Hi.
-对啊 -嗨
I know getting married in the street isn't what you approve of.
妈妈, 我知道在大街上结婚这种事 肯定不合你的脾气...
No, it's lovely. The lights and the snow. I could look at them forever.
不, 这挺有趣的, 又是灯又是雪的  我怎么看都看不够
I crushed a pill and put it in her drink.
我刚才在她的饮料里下了点药
Come on, sweetheart.
来吧, 亲爱的
You know, Chappy's too small to handle all this snow.
你们看, 恰皮太弱小了 它恐怕难以应付这一地的积雪
Someone has to walk him down the aisle.
到时候需要有人抱着它
-Would this person be in the wedding? -I guess.
-那么, 这个人也算参加了婚礼仪式吧? -我想是吧.
-I'll do it! -I'll do it!
-我来  -我来
Chandler, hello? I mean, aren't you scared of dogs?
等等, 钱德, 你不是害怕狗吗?
I'm not scared. I'll just take little Chappy and..
谁说我害怕 我只要抱着小恰皮 然后...
He can sense my fear! My throat is exposed!
它知道我害怕它!  我的嗓子都翻出来了!
I guess I'm in the wedding then.
哦, 那么我猜 出现在婚礼上的人就是我喽 哈哈!
He stinks.
它好臭
Level one alert! I repeat, level one, this is not a drill!
一级警报! 重复, 一级警报, 这不是演习!
We have a situation. The minister called. He's snowed in, he can't make it.
我们碰到难题了, 牧师刚才打电话来说 他被大雪困住,赶不过来了
-Oh, no. -Hey, don't worry.
-哦, 不是吧  -嘿, 甭担心
-I'm still ordained from your wedding. -Really?
-我在你们结婚那会儿 获得的牧师资格到现在还有效 -真的?
Yeah. You think I'd give up being a minister and pay to ride the subway?
是啊 你认为我会放弃牧师资格吗？ 那样的话我坐地铁就不能免票了！
Ministers don't ride the subway for free.
部长坐地铁也不免票
I had to read the Bible pretty carefully, but, yeah, we do.
我仔细研究过圣经的, 没错, 我们不用买票
We have to find someone else to walk Phoebe down the aisle.
Ok, 如果让乔伊来主持婚礼的话 那我们还需要有个人来挽着菲比
I'll do it!
我来! 啊哈哈...
Okay, Mike and Joey, get in position.
好, 麦克和乔伊, 各就各位
Chandler, come with me.
钱德, 跟我来
Okay, Joey's doing the ceremony, and Chandler's giving you away.
乔伊负责主持婚礼  你由钱德负责
Oh, okay. Hi, new Dad.
哦, 好 嗨, 新爹
So you ready to do this?
那么, 你准备好了么?
Oh, my God. This is really happening.
哦, 天哪, 这一切都是真的
-Phoebe, I'm so happy for you, honey. -Thank you.
-哦, 菲比, 我真替你高兴, 亲爱的  -谢谢
I love you. Wait, wait! No hugs! The dresses!
我爱你  等等, 不要抱, 当心礼服!
-Oh, what the hell. -Oh, come on.
-管它的  -来吧!
-I love you guys. -I love you.
-我爱你们, 亲爱的  -我爱你
Okay, it's zero hour! All teams execute on my count!
好了, 现在是0:00  各小组听我的指令行事
Let's get this bad boy on the road!
我们开始吧!
Is it okay I want you to wear that headset in bed?
我想让你今晚戴着这副耳机上床, 你不反对吧?
I have you scheduled for nudity at 2300 hours.
呃, 根据计划 我的裸体时间被安排在23:00
Oh, yeah.
噢耶
Okay, Marjorie, hit it.
好了, 马崔, 开始敲你的吧
-Jeez, Ross. You could've showered. -It's the dog.
-天哪, 罗斯, 你就不能先洗个澡吗  -是狗身上的味!
Groomsman? Why are you standing there? Where's your bridesmaid?
伴郎, 为什么只有你一个人站在这儿? 伴娘呢?
We've got a broken arrow! Bridesmaid down!
我们遇到情况了, 伴娘失踪了
Oh, that's me.
噢, 是我自己
-Ready? -Okay.
-准备好了么? -好了
Oh, wait. Oh, no. Wait.
哦, 等一下, 哦, 等等
Wow. Aren't you gonna be cold?
哇, 你不觉得冷吗?
I don't care.
我不在乎
I'll be my "something blue."
我要做自己的“something blue”  （象征新娘纯洁的宝物）
-You look beautiful. -Thank you.
-你看起来美极了  -谢谢
My God.
天哪
Aren't you freezing?
你不冷吗?
Friends. Family.
朋友们, 家人们
Dog.
狗儿
Thank you all for being here to witness this blessed event.
感谢你们能够到场来见证这一场天赐的姻缘
The cold has now spread to my special place..
冷空气已经蔓延到我“那里”了
so I'm gonna do the short version of this.
所以我会长话短说
Phoebe and Mike are perfect for each other.
菲比和麦克是完美的一对儿
And I know I speak for everyone here..
我相信在场的每一个人都会和我一样
when I wish them a lifetime of happiness.
祝愿他们一生幸福
And may they have many children..
愿他们有很多孩子..
who will one day avenge their family's honor.
能够为家族的荣誉而复仇
How could I not get that part? Stupid Ralph Macchio.
我怎么没得到那部分? 愚蠢的拉夫.马切奥
Right. Okay.
好
Who has the rings?
戒指呢？
Okay.
好的
When I was growing up, I didn't have a normal mom and dad..
在我成长的过程中, 我不曾拥有真正的父爱和母爱
or a regular family like everybody else.
或者和别人一样拥有一个正常的家庭
And I always knew that something was missing.
我总是觉得自己缺少了些什么
But now I'm standing here today..
然而现在, 我站在这里
knowing that I have everything I'm ever gonna need.
我知道自己已经得到了自己所需要的一切
You are my family.
你就是我的家人
Phoebe, you are so beautiful.
菲比, 你是这么的美丽
You're so kind. You're so generous.
这么的善良, 这么的大方
You're so wonderfully weird.
古怪的你是那么的迷人
Every day with you is an adventure.
和你在一起的每一天都像是一次探险
And I can't believe how lucky I am.
我简直不敢相信自己是如此地幸运
And I can't wait to share my life with you forever.
我迫不急待地想要和你分享自己的生命 直到永远
Oh, wait! Oh, I forgot. And..
哦 等一下, 我忘了说
I love you.
我爱你
And you have nice eyes.
还有, 你的眼睛很漂亮
I love you too.
我也爱你
-Joey? -Yeah?
-乔伊	 -怎么了
Chappy's heart rate has slowed way down.
Chppy的心脏越跳越慢了
Okay. Phoebe..
菲比
do you take this man to be your husband?
你愿意这个男人成为你的丈夫吗?
I do.
我愿意
Mike, do you take this woman to be your wife?
麦克, 你愿意这个女人成为你的妻子吗?
I do.
我愿意
I now pronounce you..
我现在正式宣布你们...
husband and wife.
结为夫妻
I got married!
我结婚了!
Could someone get me a coat? I'm frigging freezing.
谁递给我件衣服? 我快要冻僵了
-It really was an incredible wedding. -It was.
-真是场让人难以置信的婚礼  -是啊, 的确
I kind of don't want it to end. Hey..
我真不想让它就那么结束  嘿
you wanna come in for a drink and a bite of corsage?
你想来喝一杯吗, 还有一些襟花可以吃
I'd love to, but it's 2300 hours..
我很想去, 但现在已经23:00了
and I'm about to have the most organized sex anyone's ever had.
我现在要去 经历一次有史以来最有组织的性爱
-Whatever happened to Ross? -I don't know.
-嘿, 罗斯呢? -我不知道
Maybe he hooked up with that hot girl he talked to.
刚才他还在跟一个辣妹聊天来着 大概两个人搞在一起了吧
Come on, Chappy! Do your business!
快点, 恰皮, 拜托你快点解决了吧,
Make!
拉啊!
I did not sign on for this.
我参加婚礼可不是为了做这个